brainhost.com 2013-08-19

# Privacy Policy

## Legal and privacy issues, please address queries to:

Brain Host, LLC  
3660 Center Rd Suite 363   
Brunswick, Ohio 44212

Effective Date: 02/01/2012

Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Policy in order for you to understand how Brain Host, LLC (“Brain Host”)  collects, uses, communicates, transfers, and makes use of personal information collected on our site: www.brainhost.com. The following outlines our privacy policy.

Brian Host, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us [support [@] brainhost.com](https://web.archive.org/web/20130819082159id_/http://www.brainhost.com/privacy/support@brainhost.com).   If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe here. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site.

We will collect and use personal information solely with the objective of fulfilling those purposes specified by us and for other compatible purposes as outlined in this privacy policy, unless we obtain the consent of the individual concerned or as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

If BrainHost is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

We may retain personal information as long as we feel is necessary in our discretion for the fulfillment of the purposes outlined in this policy or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [support [@] brainhost.com](https://web.archive.org/web/20130819082159id_/http://www.brainhost.com/privacy/support@brainhost.com).

We will collect personal information such as name, email address, phone number, address, and billing information by lawful and fair means upon your consent to this privacy policy, which is indicated upon submission of this information to BrainHost. Personal data should be accurate, complete, and up to date.

We will collect and use personal information solely with the objective of fulfilling those purposes specified by us and for other compatible purposes, unless we obtain the consent of the individual concerned or as required by law. From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will contact you before we use your data for these new purposes to notify you of the policy change and to provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses.

Upon request we provide site visitors with access to all information [including proprietary information] that we maintain about them. Consumers can access this information by logging into their account and making the change within their account management center or by e-mailing us at [support [@] brainhost.com](https://web.archive.org/web/20130819082159id_/http://www.brainhost.com/privacy/support@brainhost.com).

We will protect personal information by reasonable security safeguards against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. We always use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving sensitive data exchanged with our site. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support [@] brainhost.com](https://web.archive.org/web/20130819082159id_/http://www.brainhost.com/privacy/support@brainhost.com).

With respect to cookies: We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. We use cookies to ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates and service providers is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, service providers use session ID cookies to deliver special offers, discounts, promotions and custom software.

Clear Gifs

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We will send you service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so.  For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. If you do not want to receive email from us in the future, please let us know by contacting us at support [@] brainhost.com.

Service Providers

We use other third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill you for services, an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf, a client services partner to provide account management tools and a live chat provider to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order, and trusted third party advertising partners to send you special offers and promotions that we feel may be of interest to you  You may receive these messages via phone, SMS, email or direct mail.  When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service. If you do not wish to receive advertisements from our partners please contact us at **[support [@] brainhost.com](https://web.archive.org/web/20130819082159id_/http://www.brainhost.com/privacy/support@brainhost.com) **or you may unsubscribe from particular advertisements by clicking the unsubscribe link within the advertisement.

Re-Targeted Advertising

Re-Targeted advertising uses information collected on an individual’s web browsing behavior such as the pages they have visited or the searches they have made. This information is then used to display ads. The information collected is only linked to an anonymous cookie ID (alphanumeric number); it does not include any information that could be linked back to a particular person, such as their name, address or credit card number. The information used for targeted advertising either comes from Brain Host or through third party website publishers. If you would like to opt out of re-targeted advertising from Brain Host that occurs when visiting our third party advertising publishers, please [click here](http://preferences.truste.com/truste/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Brain Host. Please be aware that we, Brain Host, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

Public Forums

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at support [@] brainhost.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will contact you before we use your data for these new purposes to notify you of the policy change and to provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at [ **support [@] brainhost.com**](https://web.archive.org/web/20130819082159id_/http://www.brainhost.com/privacy/support@brainhost.com).
